这里再次是机器人关节控制系统的框图。我们要做什么
Here again is the block diagram of a robot joint control system. What we're going to
现在要做的是为PUMA560机器人的第2关节建立一个模型。
do now is to actually build a model for joint 2 of the PUMA 560 robot.
PUMA560机器人的一个优点是它是一个研究得很好的机器人，而且
One of the advantages of the PUMA 560 robot is that it's a very well-studied robot, and
它的控制器及其机制的许多参数都非常清楚。
many of the parameters of its controller and of its mechanism are very well understood.
下面列出了该机器人关节2的一些重要参数。我们有惯性
Here are listed a few of the important parameters of joint 2 for this robot. We have the inertia
电机;我们有电机的摩擦力，电机转矩常数，放大率
of the motor; we have the friction of the motor, the motor torque constant, the amplifying
获得。这是应用于放大器的每个伏特进入电机的放大器数量。最后，
gain. That's the number of amps into the motor for every volt applied to the amplifier. Finally,
PUMA机器人第二关节的传动比。
the gear ratio for the second joint of the PUMA robot.
我刚刚将机器人动态模型的参数输入MATLAB工作区，
I have just been entering the parameters for our robot dynamic model into the MATLAB Workspace,
创建一些变量。我需要创建的最后一个是齿轮比
creating a number of variables. The last one that I need to create is the gear ratio which
PUMA机器人的这个特殊关节是107.815。
is 107.815 for this particular joint of the PUMA robot.
接下来我要做的是调用Simulink，这是用于创建和创建的MATLAB工具
Next thing I'm going to do is to invoke Simulink, which is the MATLAB tool for creating and
模拟动力学模型。调用Simulink，这是给我们所有人的窗口
simulating dynamical models. Invoked Simulink, and here is the window which gives us all
我们需要的模型的其余组件。我打算创建一个新模型，并且
the rest of the components of the models that we need. I'm going to create a new model, and
这是我可以创建新图形模型的窗口。
here's the window in which I can create my new graphical model.
现在，我要做的第一件事是添加一些连续时间的动态块。该
Now, the first thing I'm going to do is to add some continuous time dynamic blocks. The
我要做的第一件事就是拖动转移功能，这将成为我们的电机模型。
first thing I'm going to do is to drag in the transfer function which is going to be our motor model.
这是将成为我们电机的块，我将更改参数。
Here is the block which is going to be our motor, and I'm going to change the parameters.
在这种特殊情况下，分子是变量'km'，即电机转矩常数，
The numerator in this particular case is the variable 'km,' that's the motor torque constant,
分母是多项式，最高阶系数是'jm'，即
and the denominator is a polynomial, and the highest order coefficient is 'jm,' that's
电机惯性跟随电机摩擦，然后是零。这是一个二阶
the motor inertia followed by the motor friction and followed by a zero. It is a second-order
多项式。我们走了。
polynomial. There we go.
在这里，我们有一个代表我们电机动力学的块。我也打算画
Here, we have a block which represents the dynamics of our motor. I'm also going to draw
在PID控制器中，那就是它。我要创建一个源代码。这是
in a PID controller, and that's it there. I'm going to create a source. This is the
表示我希望机器人关节跟随。我要拖进信号发生器和
signal that I want the robot joint to follow. I'm going to drag in a signal generator and
我打算把它设置为0.5赫兹的频率。
I'm going to set it to have a frequency of 0.5 Hertz.
这是每两秒一个周期，它将是一个方波，我要去
That's one cycle every two seconds, and it’s going to be a square wave and I'm going to
将其连接到我的控制器的参考输入。我要设置控制器
connect that to the reference input of my controller. I'm going to set the controller
参数比例增益为1，积分增益为0，依此类推。
parameters a proportional gain of 1, integral gain of 0, and so on.
现在我们已经准备好模拟系统了。我要在参考中应用方波
Now we're ready to simulate the system. I'm going to apply a square wave to the reference
输入我的控制器。
input of my controller.
在真实机器人中，控制器的输出是一个电压到达电机驱动器，
In the real robot, the output of the controller is a voltage which goes to the motor drive,
这实际上是一个大功率放大器，其输出是电流
which is effectively a big power amplifier, and the output of that is a current which
流入电机。此块表示电机的动态特性和输出
flows into the motor. This block here represents the dynamics of the motor, and the output
是电机的位置。我们可以看到反馈路径。我要做的就是点击
is the position of the motor. We can see the feedback path. What I'm going to do is hit
这里的“播放”按钮，Simulink将模拟这个动态模型。
the 'Play' button here, and Simulink is going to simulate this dynamic model.
在这里，我们看到输出响应。我们可以看到电机以某种方式响应
Here we see the output response. We can see that the motor is responding in some way to
正在注入的方波，但我们可以看到它非常振荡，
the square wave, which is being injected, but we can see that it's very very oscillatory,
那里有很多超调，这是非常不受欢迎的。
there's a lot of overshoot there which is very undesirable.
我们可以调整控制器的参数。我要做的是添加一点
We can adjust the parameters of the controller. What I’m going to do is to add a little
微分导数，也称为阻尼。
bit of derivative gain, otherwise known as damping.
如果我现在模拟，那就是导数增益设置为0.1的值。我们在这里看到
If I simulated now, that's where the derivative gain is set to a value of 0.1. Here we see
反应更令人满意。我们看到电机位置在变化之间
the response is much more desirable. We see that the motor position is changing between
-1和+1。这正是这个信号发生器所要求的。我们看到了
-1 and +1. That's exactly what this signal generator is demanding. We see that there's
只有极少量的过冲。这不是一个坏的机器人联合控制器。
only a very small amount of overshoot. This is not a bad robot joint controller.
我们使用一些试验和错误来使该控制器正常工作。虽然是的
We use a little bit of trial and error to make this controller work well. Although it's
这样做很常见，更好的方法是设计控制器
quite common practice to do this, a much better approach is to design the controller that
要求我们有一个要控制的系统模型。在PUMA机器人的情况下，
requires we have a model of the system to be controlled. In the case of the PUMA robot,
我们确实有一个非常非常好的机器人模型，机械和电气元件。
we do have a very, very good model of that robot, of its mechanical and its electrical components.
然后我们需要有一个控制质量的规范。超调量是多少
Then we need to have a specification for the quality of control. How much overshoot are
我们愿意容忍吗？我们希望机器人关节多快达到所需的关节角度？
we willing to tolerate? How quickly do we want the robot joint to get to the desired joint angle?
然后我们使用控制理论中众所周知的技术，如“根轨迹法”或
Then we use well-known techniques from control theory such as, 'Root locus method,' or
'极点放置'或'LQR合成'。
'pole placement' or 'LQR synthesis'.
控制理论中有很多技术。选择你喜欢的那个，然后申请
There are lots of techniques in control theory. Pick the one that you prefer, and you apply
那是设计一个控制器。也许它需要一点点调整，也许是因为
that to design a controller. Perhaps it needs a little bit of tweaking, perhaps because
您正在使用的模型并不能完全反映特定机器人的实际情况
the model that you're using doesn't exactly reflect the reality of the particular robot
你正在努力，但你会得到一个非常好的第一近似一个体面的控制器。
that you're working on, but you'll get a very very good first approximation to a decent controller.
对于像PUMA560这样的多关节机器人，常见的策略就是所谓的“独立”
For a multi-joint robot like the PUMA 560, a common strategy is what's called, 'Independent
联合控制。'我们为每个单独的关节设计和构建一个控制器。
Joint Control.' We design and build a controller for each of these separate joints.
对于规模经济，每个控制器使用相同的设计是很常见的
For economies of scale, it's common to use the same design for the controller for each
的关节。所有不同的是联合控制算法中的一些参数
of the joints. All that's different is some parameters in the joint control algorithm
反映关节有不同动态的事实。也许他们有所不同
to reflect the fact that the joints have got different dynamics. Perhaps they have different
尺寸马​​达`具有不同的惯性，不同的摩擦特性等。
size motors` with different inertia, different friction characteristics, and so on.